TENGOKU-DAIMAKYO Push Start!
《天国大魔境》 （推动发车）
What? It floats into the sky and shoots out light?
什么？它飞上了天空而且还发出光芒？
What kind of face does it have?
它长什么样子啊？
Don't ask me everything. Imagine for yourself, Kona.
别什么都只会问我，你自己想象，小奈
Close your eyes,
闭上双眼
and focus on what comes to mind. Look at it closely.
专注于脑海出现的画面，仔细看
It might be something you think you saw out of the corner of your eye,
可能是你眼角余光瞄到的东西
or an optical illusion.
或者是视错觉
But let it fill your senses. Follow it.
但就让它充满你的感官，跟随着它
Did you see something?
看到什么了吗？
A sword of light?
一道剑光？
-Michika? -Blood.
-美智香？ -流血了
What's happened?
怎么回事？
-Michika suddenly started bleeding. -Get the teacher!
-美智香突然开始流血 -快去报告老师
It's a deep cut.
伤口很深
No one even touched Michika. It came out of nowhere.
根本没有人碰到美智香，突然就变成这样
Michika, please stay still.
美智香，请不要动
It's not perfect, so please rest, okay?
还没有完全复原，你好好休息，好吗？
Kona? Kona.
小奈？小奈
What? Asura?
什么？亚思拉？
When did you come in?
你什么时候来的？
-Oh, no! -A power outage?
-怎么搞的？ -停电了吗？
No, wait. It's just the camera monitors.
不对，等等，只有监视器的画面停掉了
Restart them!
重新启动
CAMERAS ARE NOT RESPONDING
（屏幕没有反应）
Now I understand why I was born.
小奈，我现在知道我出生的原因了
So I have come to say goodbye.
所以我是来说再见的
What?
什么？
Asura?
亚思拉？
Asura!
亚思拉
Asura, where are you?
亚思拉，你在哪里？
The adults are on their way.
大人正在路上了
Go back to your room, Kona.
回去你的房间，小奈
Asura, don't go!
亚思拉，别走
I'll be all alone!
我会很孤单
You are not alone.
你不孤单
You have Anzu, Tokio and Mimihime.
你有杏、时男和弥美姬
Even Nanaki, Iwa and the others.
还有七贵、伊波和其他人
You will find more and more friends.
你的朋友会越来越多
Kona, find someone that you love.
小奈，找到你爱的人
But I love you, Asura!
但我爱你啊，亚思拉
It's a different kind of love. An even more special feeling.
是不一样的爱，那是一种更特别的感觉
Open your heart to it.
敞开你的心房去感受
Kona seems lonely.
小奈看起来好寂寞
Kona is the only one left in his year now.
小奈那个年级，只剩下他一个了
I'll be right back.
我很快就回来
Tokio!
时男
What is it, Tokio?
怎么了，时男？
It's nothing important…
没什么重要的啦
but I just thought I'd come over here.
我只是想说过来一下
You're so good at drawing.
你好会画画哦
Thank you.
谢谢
Whoever killed Asura,
杀了亚思拉的人
is coming to take Tokio away next.
接下来就会过来把时男带走
CHILDREN OF THE NURSERY
《学园的孩子们》
That was so close.
很危险耶
They are the group of 14-year-olds.
他们是14岁的孩子
That's great.
太好了
Tokio? Could it be?
时男？不会吧？
And a group of 15 five-year-olds will join the nursery.
即将会有一群15岁的孩子加入学园
They will probably be the last.
他们很可能是最后一批了
Oh, Miss Aoshima, what are you doing?
青岛小姐，你在做什么？
I need you to interpret.
我需要你帮忙翻译
Sorry.
抱歉
Usami was holding this button. It has the same logo as Kiru-Beam.
宇佐美手里握着这颗钮扣 跟贵留光线上的记号一模一样
It can't just be a coincidence.
这不可能只是巧合而已
Since you only have a vague idea of where you're trying to go,
既然你对于你的目的地没有明确的概念
I think tracking down this logo is a good idea.
追踪这个记号或许是个好主意
So the next place we need to go is--
所以我们下一个该前往的地方是…
The town where Usami used to live?
宇佐美之前居住的城镇？
That's the one.
就是那里
I thought we'd be going that way with Usami,
我以为我们会和宇佐美一起走
so I didn't see where he pointed on the map.
所以他在地图上指出那里时 我没有仔细看
Everyone else went off that way.
大家都往那个方向走
Yeah, but if they turned off here or there…
对，但如果他们在这里或那里转了个弯…
If they did that, then there are endless possibilities.
若是这样的话，就会有无限多种可能性耶
Don't make it sound like a good thing.
你那种口气，好像这是件好事一样
Well, either way, we've just got to try to get there.
无论如何，我们总得想办法去到那里
Oh, and by the way, look.
对了，你看
The tooth that fell out. It's growing back.
断掉的那颗牙齿又长出来了耶
What's going on with your body?
你的身体究竟是怎么回事？
-An earthquake. -It's a big one.
-地震 -是个大地震
Careful! If the ground swallows you up, you're done for.
小心，掉下去的话，你就完了
There hasn't been an earthquake in ages.
几百年没出现过地震了
That must be a building falling nearby.
附近一定有大楼倒塌
-Let's go. -What for?
-走吧 -做什么？
When a building falls down,
大楼倒塌之后
you can get into any room. It's a total jackpot.
你就能随意进出每个房间，等于是中乐透
If it's near the town we're looking for, resource collectors might show up.
如果刚好位于我们正在寻找的城镇附近 或许会有回收人员出没
You wanna grab anything worth stealing before those guys?
你想要抢在那些人之前 把值钱的东西搜括一空吗？
You idiot. They can take us to the place we're looking for.
笨蛋，他们就可以带我们 前往我们正在寻找的地方啦
It didn't collapse completely. It'll be dangerous.
尚未完全倒塌，可能会有危险
We can get in this way.
我们可以从这里进去
Give it up. If it caves in, we'll die.
算了吧，如果塌方的话，我们就死定了
What the hell? Someone's living in there!
搞什么啊？有人住在里面
Oh, wow, are you okay?
你没事吧？
You did well to survive.
你的生存之道还真不是盖的
No, no. I don't live there.
不是啦，我不住在这里
I came to have a look to see if there are any resources.
我只是来这里看看是否有可用的资源
Looks like you beat us to it.
看来你抢先了我们一步
Sorry.
抱歉
I couldn't get in at all, and I don't have anything either.
我完全进不去 而且我身上什么东西都没有
Can you let it slide?
你们可以放我一马吗？
What are you so nervous for?
你干嘛这么紧张？
Well, from the look of you, aren't you guys bandits?
从两位的外型看来，你们不是强盗吗？
Who you calling bandits?
你说谁是强盗？
You stink of bandits way more than us!
你才比我们更像强盗咧
I-I'm sorr…
对不起啦
I'm sorry for taking up your time.
不好意思打扰了
Please excuse me for calling you here so suddenly.
我突然叫你过来，请你不要介意
It's okay. I've been anxious about my health recently too.
没关系 反正最近我也一直在担心我的健康
Thank you for checking up on me.
谢谢你帮我做检查
Everything seems perfectly okay, so no need to worry.
一切看来都相当完美，完全不用担心
For now, just try not to catch a chill.
从现在开始，尽量注意别着凉了
And don't do any strenuous activity.
也不要做任何剧烈活动
Okay. I won't.
好的，我知道了
Mimihime.
弥美姬
You made me jump.
你吓了我一跳
Don't sneak up on me like that.
不要这样偷偷靠近我啦
You're always looking at something up there.
你总是会一直看着那边的某个东西
And you're always looking at me.
而你总是一直看着我
Is it the ceiling?
你在看天花板吗？
It's something floating in front of the ceiling.
是漂浮在天花板前面的东西
Dust?
灰尘？
If you're talking about specks of light floating about,
如果你说的是漂浮的发光粒子
they're particles in your eyes' vitreous fluid.
那是你眼睛玻璃体上的浮游物哦
Anyway, let's go. Class is about to start.
总之，我们走吧，上课时间要到了
I see.
是哦
Just as I thought.
跟我想的一样
I'm the only one who can see it.
只有我看得见
It's creepy.
好恐怖
Really? Can no one else see that?
真的吗？别人都看不见吗？
Is everyone present?
全都到齐了吗？
Tokio isn't here yet.
时男还没来
Before class begins,
开始上课之前
I need to inform you of something about Tokio.
我跟大家说明一下有关时男的事
-You may not see Tokio for some time. -What?
-你们有好一阵子不会见到时男 -什么？
But, of course, you will meet again.
但是，你们当然会再见面的
Please don't worry.
请别担心
Let's begin the class.
开始上课
There.
好了
Must be nice to have a car that works.
有一台功能正常的车一定很棒吧
It's not as useful as you might think, when the roads are such a mess.
如果路状很差的话 就不是你以为的那么便利了
Well, I'm all set then.
那我也该告辞咯
Isn't it dangerous by yourself?
你自己一个人不是很危险吗？
Worst-case scenario, I've got this.
遇到最糟糕的状况，我也还有这个
You had something that dangerous hidden under your raincoat?
你在雨衣里藏了这么危险的东西？
Well, isn't that a gun?
那不是一把枪吗？
Something like that.
算是吧
Hey, is there a town somewhere round here?
这附近有城镇吗？
Information is a commodity, you know.
资讯是商品，你懂吗？
If it's money you want, we'll pay.
如果你要的是钱，我们会付钱
In any case, do either of these guys, this logo,
总而言之，你对这些人、这个记号
or the word "heaven" mean anything to you?
或者「天国」这两个字有任何印象吗？
Wait there a minute.
请两位等等
I just need to move the car a bit. Can you step back?
我得先把车移过去一点 请你们后退好吗？
A bit further! A bit more!
再远一点，再一点
There. Now we can talk properly.
好了，现在我们可以好好聊了
I get the feeling I might know where that logo comes from.
我感觉我可能知道那个记号是来自何处
Oh, really?
真的吗？
I'll tell you in exchange for the gun.
你给我那把枪，我就告诉你
It's not for sale.
这是非卖品
In that case, money will do.
这样的话，给我钱也可以
That was easy.
小事一桩
Well, there's no point complaining and getting myself killed.
没必要嫌东嫌西，让我的小命不保
But it may take me a little while to remember.
但我可能需要一些时间才想得起来
I make a living selling the information I have.
我是靠贩售情报讨生活
I'm sure once I get talking it'll jog my memory.
我很肯定一旦我开始说起这件事 我就会慢慢想起来
This guy is really milking it.
这家伙真的是无所不用其极
Just tell us whichever one you think is best.
就说说你认为最棒的那个情报吧
Good evening, everyone.
各位晚安
I have returned once more.
我又回来了
I, Juichi, am here to tell you
我名叫充一，在这里向各位诉说
stories that may have really happened.
或许真正发生过的故事
It's still daytime.
现在还是大白天
There are various rumors about what caused the Great Disaster.
关于造成大灾难的原因众说纷纭
But why does the cause remain so unclear?
为何原因至今仍不清不楚呢？
Because the subsequent earthquakes, the abnormally long winters,
那是因为之后就发生了地震 然后又遇上了异常漫长的冬天
the famine and disease, led humanity towards the edge of extinction,
饥荒和疾病导致人类濒临绝种
making it impossible to trace back to what originally happened.
因而无从追溯真正的事发原因
These three theories persist.
有三个理论一直存在着
1 ASTEROID IMPACT 2 ALIEN INVASION - 3 WAR THEORY
（1.小行星撞击说 2.外星人入侵说，3.战争说）
First is the asteroid impact theory.
首先是小行星撞击说
Before the Great Disaster, people were making a lot of noise
在大灾难之前，大家就纷纷议论着
about the discovery of an asteroid drawing closer to Earth.
发现了一颗越来越靠近地球的小行星
The sheer scale of the disaster makes this theory a strong one.
灾难规模惊人 使得这个说法的可信度很高
Next, the alien invasion theory.
接下来是外星人入侵说
It may seem absurd at first, but some people think
乍听之下令人觉得很可笑，但有些人认为
that those man-eating life-forms came to Earth from space.
那些吃人的生命体 就是从外太空来到地球的
Before the Great Disaster occurred,
在大灾难发生之前
many people witnessed mysterious figures floating in the sky.
很多人目击到谜样的生物飞翔在空中
I managed to get hold of this precious image from back then.
我取得了在当时拍摄到的珍贵影像
That's a bird.
那是一只鸟
Finally, the war theory.
最后是战争说
There is a rumor that before the Great Disaster,
在大灾难发生前有个谣言
there was a terrorist attack somewhere in Japan.
关于日本某处发生了恐怖攻击
The theory goes that this caused an outbreak of war
这个理论主张这场攻击引发了战争
and the use of some sort of special weapon.
并且使用了某种特殊的武器
So, how was the story?
这个故事你们觉得如何？
Well, let's meet again sometime for another story.
那么，下次有机会的话 再告诉你们另一则故事咯
See you. Bye-bye.
先走咯，拜拜
It's not "See you. Bye-bye"!
「先走咯，拜拜」个什么劲呀？
Did you remember anything about the logo or not?
你到底记不记得有关这个记号的事？
Oops. Maybe if I keep talking it'll come back to me.
唉呀，如果我继续说下去的话 可能会想起来哦
I knew you'd say that!
我就知道你会说这一句
Cool it, Sis. Let's just hear one more, at least.
姐，冷静，至少再多讲一个故事吧？
MENU - GREAT DISASTER TRUE GHOST STORIES
（选项：大灾难，真实鬼故事）
Tell us one of the true ghost stories. "The Walled Town."
说说「围墙小镇」这个真实的鬼故事吧
Thank you.
谢谢
Then let's get back to it.
那我就回到正题咯
This story is one of my own, experienced firsthand.
这则故事是我的亲身经历，第一手资料
For ten years, from the age of 12,
我从12岁开始，有十年的时间
I was shut up in a school surrounded by walls.
被关在一个被围墙包围的学校
I apologize for calling an emergency meeting with everyone.
很抱歉临时召集大家开紧急会议
Mina will send out meeting minutes to the departments who cannot attend.
美娜会将会议纪录寄给不克前来的部门
First, in regards to the ongoing search for an assistant director,
首先，关于物色助理园长人选一事
I would like to ask Miss Aoshima to take up the position.
我想请青岛小姐接任这个位子
Miss Aoshima will be given level-four access rights.
青岛小姐将取得等级四的授权
Hold on one second.
等等
Why is Aoshima being promoted?
晋升青岛的理由是什么？
Because Miss Aoshima is the one I can trust the most.
因为青岛小姐是我最信任的人
But Dr. Sawatari was supposed to be the most likely future director.
但猿渡医生才应该是 最有可能成为未来园长的人选吧
This is not going to go down well.
这样下去一定会出问题
Madame Takeuchi too.
竹内女士也有同感
That town was a place where women ruled.
那个城镇受到女性的统治
There were around 30 women, mostly between the ages of 20 and 40.
大概有30位女性 大部分介于20岁到40岁之间
The school was their stronghold, and they barricaded it in.
这所学校是她们的大本营 她们在四面八方筑起了屏障
Any man who accidentally approached it would be killed.
不小心接近了这所学校的男人都会被杀害
However, in rare cases,
但仍有极为少数的例外
if they thought the man was healthy and liked his face,
如果她们喜欢这个男人的长相 觉得他很健康
they would imprison him in the town, keeping him as a "breeding pig."
她们就会将他囚禁起来 将他当成「种猪」看待
I spent ten years in that town, as Boar #11.
我以种猪11号的身份在那个城镇待了十年
The breeding pigs would perform tasks and provide the women with sperm.
种猪要负责各种杂务 也需要提供精子给女人
When it was my turn, one couple kept asking for me.
轮到我的时候 有一对情侣经常会指名要我
Eventually, one of them fell pregnant.
最终其中一位怀孕了
If a girl was born, she would be accepted into the town as a human.
如果生的是女儿 就会被这个城镇当成人类看待
But if it was a boy, he would be taken from his mother
但如果生的是儿子 他就会被带离母亲身边
and raised by us as a breeding pig.
以种猪的身份被抚养成人
It was a boy.
结果是个男孩
One night, about six months later, that couple hatched a plan.
大约是六个月后的某个晚上 那对情侣密谋了一个计划
The four of us would flee the town together.
我们四人打算逃离那座城镇
Yeah! Good for you!
好耶，做得好
But they found us…
但被她们发现了
and only I barely managed to escape.
只有我千钧一发地逃脱成功
The next day,
隔天
the couple's slaughtered corpses had been strung up outside the town walls.
这对情侣被屠杀的尸体 就被吊在城镇外面的墙上
About one year has passed since then.
这是一年前的事了
That such a terrifying place can even exist in this world, is…
竟然有这么可怕的地方存在于这个世上…
So let's meet again sometime for another story.
那么，下次有机会的话 再告诉你们另一则故事咯
See you. Bye-bye.
先走咯，拜拜
It's not "See you. Bye bye"!
「先走咯，拜拜」个什么劲呀？
What happened to the baby?
那个孩子后来怎么样了？
I don't know.
我不知道
What a gruesome story.
好可怕的故事哦
Sis, can't you go check somehow? To see if the baby is at least alive?
姐，你不能去确认看看吗？ 看看那个孩子是否还活着？
If the story is even true…
谁知道这故事是不是真的…
I suppose you did tell us a story, so I won't take the money back.
你的确是说了一个故事 所以我不会把钱要回来
But you better get lost before I kill you.
但在我杀了你之前，你快滚吧
I-I'm sorry!
很抱歉
What was that for?
你这是在干嘛？
He didn't tell us about the logo yet.
他还没跟我们说记号的事
He didn't need to.
没有那个必要了
That guy was acting really strange.
那家伙怪里怪气的
Even though the driver's seat is on the right,
驾驶座明明是在右侧
he went to the effort to repark his car to the right.
他却自找麻烦地把车停靠在右侧
In the first place,
一开始
why park your car so close to the wall, when there's no one around here?
他就把车紧贴着墙面停靠 但这里根本一个人也没有呀？
There was a reason he needed to move it so quickly.
一定有某种原因让他必须赶紧这么做
He spotted something that he wanted to hide.
他注意到了某个不想让我们看到的东西
2F - TAKA
（二楼）
TAKAHARA ACADEMY
（高原学园）
It's the logo on the Kiru-Beam.
这是贵留光线上的记号
We nearly wasted all our time and money on that endless storytelling.
我们花钱听的那些没完没了的故事 根本是在浪费时间
But we found it.
但我们找到了
The origin of the symbol.
记号的来源
TAKAHARA ACADEMY
（高原学园）
That box!
那个箱子
You found it.
被你看到了
You really are an odd-job girl.
你真不愧是个专门打零工的女孩
We found the Kiru-Beam logo,
我们找到了贵留光线的记号
but if this is heaven, isn't it really just a normal building?
但如果这里是天国… 这不过就是个寻常的大楼吗？
Let's look around some more.
我们再四处看看吧
Someone's already scavenged through all this stuff.
这栋大楼已经有人搜刮过了
"Welcome message from the Director.
（自然财富运作）
At Takahara Academy, there is a space where you can rest both body and mind.
高原学园是一个 让你的身心灵都能安歇的地方
There is time to immerse yourself in your hobbies,
有时间让你沉浸在自己的爱好里
and people who will listen to you in times of stress."
在你感到压力时 有人愿意聆听你的心声」
HELL OF PATIENCE
（耐心地狱）
Just one more thing I don't understand about life before the Great Disaster.
关于大灾难之前的生活 我又多了一件不了解的事
Seems like an orphanage you can go to even if you have a family and home…
这似乎是个让有家可归的人 也可以去的孤儿院
EDUCATIONAL INSTITUTION TAKAHARA ACADEMY
（教育机构） （高原学园）
…and it's also a cram school?
同时也是一间补习班？
The heaven-like civilization of that period sounds like hard work.
那个时期如同天堂的文明 听起来也挺辛苦的
Well, maybe not all that bad.
或许也没那么糟糕啦
With a few friends, maybe I'd have the patience for it.
有一些朋友陪在身边 我也许会有足够的耐心面对
Sis! Will you come here?
姐，过来一下好吗？
TAKAHARA ACADEMY
（高原学园）
Was this floor part of Takahara Academy too?
这层楼也属于高原学园吗？
Over here.
过来这里
Another weird bird mark.
又一个奇怪的鸟记号
But it just looks like someone made a graffiti version of the other one.
但这看起来像是有人 在墙上随意涂鸦那个记号
I bet bandits lived here at some point.
一定有强盗在这里住过一段时间
I'm not sure how,
我无法解释
but I get the feeling this place isn't the one I've been searching for.
但我总觉得这个地方 不是我一直在找寻的目的地
And there's no one here who looks like me.
而且这里没有长得像我的人
I got all excited after we traced the logo on the gun to this place,
我们追踪枪上的记号来到了这个地方 让我一时感到很兴奋
but there's also the possibility
但也有可能
that the gun and the place I'm looking for never had any connection.
那把枪和我正在找寻的地方完全无关
What's this?
这是什么？
It seems that Takahara Academy was some kind of orphanage.
高原学园似乎是某种孤儿院
And in that guide, it describes the world as a "Hell of Patience."
简介函的内容将这个世界 描写着成「耐心地狱」
And what's the opposite of hell, Maru?
地狱的相反是什么，小丸？
Heaven.
天国
So if the symbol and this academy are related to heaven,
如果这个记号和这个学园与天国有关
I still think it's worth following this lead.
我仍然认为值得继续追踪下去
CONTACT NUMBERS
（联络电话）
According to the leaflet,
根据传单的内容
Takahara Academy has two facilities and 18 branches.
高原学园有两间设施和18所分校
I guess the other branches could be similar to this one.
我猜这些分校跟这里应该差不多
I'm more curious about the two facilities.
我更感兴趣的是这两间设施
Ibaraki and Nara?
茨城和奈良？
It seems like an okay place to sleep. Should we stay here tonight?
这里看起来还蛮适合留宿的 我们今晚要睡在这里吗？
No. Let's find somewhere else.
不要，我们找别的地方吧
This place gives me the shivers.
这个地方让我有点毛毛的
Let's get onto the main topic.
现在进入正题吧
We have discovered that Tokio is pregnant.
我们发现时男怀孕了
-What? -B-B-But that's outrageous!
-什么？ -但…这太夸张了吧！
At that young age!
在这么小的年纪！
That's not the issue.
问题不在那里
The real question is the father!
真正的问题在于孩子的爸爸是谁
-Who is the father? -Director?
-父亲是谁？ -园长？
It's under investigation!
目前正在调查当中
We never taught them the concept of sex,
我们从来没教过他们性别的概念
or the distinction between male and female.
也没教导他们男女有别
And now, in these crucial final moments…
但现在，在最后的关键时刻…
This could shake up the entire Takahara Academy!
这很可能会撼动整个高原学园
We are in a state of crisis!
危机就在眼前